Forced to host the enemy. Tormented by intruders. Tempted by desire.
Suite Française is a drama, romance, war film directed by Saul Dibb.
France, 1940.
In the first days of occupation, beautiful Lucile Angellier is trapped in a stifled existence with her
controlling mother-in-law as they both await news of her husband: a prisoner of war.
Parisian refugees start to pour into their small town, soon followed by a regiment of
German soldiers who take up residence in the villagers' own homes.
Lucile initially tries to ignore Bruno von Falk, the handsome
and refined German officer staying with them.
But soon, a powerful love draws them together and
leads them into the tragedy of war.
Lucille Angellier, played by Michelle Williams.
Madame Angellier, played by Kristin Scott Thomas.
Lieutenant Bruno Von Falk, played by Matthias Schoenaerts.
Benoit Labarie, played by Sam Riley.
Madeleine Labarie, played by Ruth Wilson.
Major, played by Heino Ferch.
Suite Française is a 2015 war romantic drama film directed by
Saul Dibb and co-written with Matt Charman.
It is based on the second part of Irène
Némirovsky's 2004 novel of the same name.
The film stars Michelle Williams, Kristin Scott Thomas, Matthias
Schoenaerts, Sam Riley, Ruth Wilson, Lambert Wilson and Margot Robbie.
It concerns a romance between a French villager and a German soldier during the
early years of the German occupation of France during World War II.
Suite Française was filmed on location in France and Belgium.
It was released theatrically in the UK on 13 March 2015 and premiered in
the US through Lifetime cable network on 22 May 2017.
The film was nominated for a Primetime Emmy Award
for Outstanding Music Composition.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, world war ii,
prisoner of war, forbidden love, french resistance.
The tone is emotional.